const qBank = [
	{
		id: 1,
		question: "Which among the following peaks is known as “Five Treasures of Great Snow”?",
		options: ["Kanchenjunga", "Lhotse", "Dhaulagiri", "Godwin Austen"],
		answer: "Kanchenjunga",
	},
	{
		id: 2,
		question: "The Grand Trunk Road or GT Road is one of South Asia’s oldest and longest major roads. It traverses through_______?",
		options: ["India & Pakistan Only", " India & Bangladesh Only", "India & Bhutan", "India, Pakistan & Bangladesh"],
		answer: "India, Pakistan & Bangladesh",
	},
	{
		id: 3,
		question: "Which of the following state of India touches maximum state boundaries?",
		options: ["Karnataka", "Uttar Pradesh", " Madhya Pradesh", "Andhra Pradesh"],
		answer: "Uttar Pradesh"
	},
	{
		id: 4,
		question: "The Karakoram Pass links _______ and ________",
		options: ["Afghanistan and Pakistan", "Afghanistan and Iran", "China and India", "China and Pakistan"],
		answer: "China and India"
	},
	{
		id: 5,
		question: "Which city is known as Manchester of India? ",
		options: ["Ahmedabad", "Lucknow", "Kolkata ", "Agra"],
		answer: "Ahmedabad"
	},
	{
		id: 6,
		question: "The Lakshadweep Islands are situated in:",
		options: ["Arabian sea", "Bay of Bengal", "Indian Ocean", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Arabian sea"
	},
    {
		id: 7,
		question: "In which of the following plains Dry farming is extensively practiced?",
		options: ["Punjab plains", "Coromandel plains", "Deccan plains", "Kanara plains"],
		answer: "Deccan plains"
	},
	
	{
		id: 8,
		question: " __________is the oldest oil field in India and still producing oil",
		options: ["Ankleshwar", "Bombay High", "Digboi", "Naharkatiya"],
		answer: "Digboi"
	},
	{
		id: 9,
		question: "Which is the largest Earthquake measured on the seismograph?",
		options: ["The Good Friday Earthquake", "Tangshan Earthquake", "Chilean Earthquake", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Chilean Earthquake"
	},
	{
		id: 10,
		question: "Which of the following mountain range separates Europe and Asia?",
		options: ["Rocky Mountain Range", "Himalayan Mountain Range", "Ural Mountain Range", "Appalachian Mountain Range"],
		answer: "Ural Mountain Range"
	},
	{
		id: 11,
		question: "Suez Canel connects which of the following water bodies?",
		options: ["Mediterranean Sea and Black Sea", "Mediterranean Sea and Red Sea", "Mediterranean Sea and Arctic Ocean", "Pacific Ocean and Atlantic Ocean"],
		answer: "Mediterranean Sea and Red Sea"
	},
	{
		id: 12,
		question: " Which of the following crops is a major source of protein in a vegetarian diet?",
		options: ["Wheat", "Rice", "Pulses", "Oilseeds"],
		answer: "Pulses"
	},
	{
		id: 13,
		question: "On which continent is the Sahara Desert located?",
		options: ["Africa", "South America", "Europe", "Asia"],
		answer: "Africa"
	},
	{
		id: 14,
		question: "Which is the largest port in India?",
		options: ["Gujarat", "Goa", "Mumbai", "Chennai"],
		answer: "Mumbai"
	},
	{
		id: 15,
		question: "How tall is Mount Everest?",
		options: ["6,849 m", "7,849 m", "8,849 m", "9,849 m"],
		answer: "8,849 m"
	},
	{
		id: 16,
		question: "Which of one the below state is the leading producer of bauxite?",
		options: ["Orissa", "Rajasthan", "Madhya Pradesh", "Nagaland"],
		answer: "Orissa"
	},
	{
		id: 17,
		question: " Which of the below port is known as “Jewel of all Port”?",
		options: ["Kochi", "Chennai", "Mumbai", "Visakhapatnam"],
		answer: "Visakhapatnam"
	},
	{
		id: 18,
		question: "The main food crop of Rabi season is:",
		options: ["Rice", "Wheat", "Jowar", "Maize"],
		answer: "Wheat"
	},
	{
		id: 19,
		question: "Which of the following is known as “coffee port” of the world?",
		options: ["Rio di Janeiro", "Santos", "Buenos Aires", "Santiago"],
		answer: "Santos"
	},
	{
		id: 20,
		question: "The Western Ghats are also known as:",
		options: ["The Sahyadris", "Sivalik Range", "Greater Mountain range", "Satpuda Range"],
		answer: "The Sahyadris"
	},
	{
		id: 21,
		question: "The largest mangrove forest in the world is located in:",
		options: ["Kerala", "Madhya Pradesh", "West Bengal", "Assam"],
		answer: "West Bengal"
	},
	{
		id: 22,
		question: "The largest Indian mammal is:",
		options: ["Tiger", "The Lion", "Hippopotamus", "Elephant"],
		answer: "Elephant"
	},
	{
		id: 23,
		question: "The longest dam in India is ______:",
		options: ["Kosi Dam", "Hirakud Dam", "Nagarjuna Sagar Dam", "Bhakra Dam"],
		answer: "Hirakud Dam"
	},
	{
		id: 24,
		question: "A group of populations of different species living in the same habitat and interacting with one another is called:",
		options: ["Ecological Community", "Zoological Community", "Biological Community", "None of the above"],
		answer: "Ecological Community"
	},
	{
		id: 25,
		question: "Indian state known as garden spice is:",
		options: ["Karnataka", "Munnar", "Kerala", "Sikkim"],
		answer: "Kerala"
	},
]

export default qBank;



















































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































































